## Eric Baranowski, Enterprise Architect

eric@kulado.com | (424) 258-5236 | Salt Lake City, Utah, US

https://twitter.com/KuladoInc | https://github.com/ericbaranowski | https://www.linkedin.com/in/ericbaranowski

#### **SUMMARY**

Proven executive and enterprise architect with extensive experience in a broad range of industries. Self-taught software developer and DevOps advocate, my primary focus is on transforming and enhancing IT in order to better align with business strategy and achieve business objectives. Specialties range from ITIL strategy and transformation, enterprise architecture, and cloud infrastructure, to application design and development, product vision, and operations management. Skilled in a broad variety of development tools, platforms and methodologies. I combine my passion for [attempting to] automate everything I touch with my 10 years of operations experience and research in helping businesses reduce risk and downtime. I am also a very creative and competent troubleshooter with a lot of practical experience, my love and support for open source initiatives can prove it.

### **EXPERIENCE**

**VirtuaaS by Kulado Inc. - Austin, TX., Lead Architect/Engineer** 2016-06-15 — 2017-10-31 https://virtuaas.com

- VirtuaaS is a cloud-platform technology based on a proprietary universal automation algorithm that is designed to assist in automating Enterprise Architecture and ITIL.
- Created a high availability HIPPA Compliant cloud infrastructure to deliver remote Workspaces as a Service.
- Partnered with Microsoft, Intuit, Cisco, Citrix, TechData, and several others to provide an agnostic approach to rapid changing business demands.

# Kulado Inc. - Salt Lake City, UT., CEO/President https://kulado.com

2014-01-27 — 2017-10-31

• Kulado Inc. is an enterprise architecture consulting firm specializing in BPA and ITIL.

- Built a fully automated IVR for a security firm using the Twilio API. Eliminated the need for over five full-time call center employees, saving the company over \$20,000 its first month. Volume was roughly 200 calls/day.
- Created an automated hosting platform with WHM/cPanel and WHMCS. Provisioning was
  fully automated on Microsoft Azure. Utilized various API's to integrate account management
  and provisioning. Ceated an algorithm that continuously pulled the lowest cost from various
  3rd party providers and passed the savings down to the consumer.
- Developed and integrated several custom Salesforce implementations for Financial Service Consultants.

Vida Capital Inc./Magna Life Settlements – Austin, TX., Enterprise/ITIL Consultant
http://vidacapitalinc.com/http://magnalifesettlements.com
2016-02-15 — 2016-06-25

- Vida Capital is an institutional asset manager focused exclusively on providing longevity-contingent investment solutions to institutions and individual investors.
- Unified communications across both organizations with Slack, Office365, and their local telecom provider.
- Designed converted and learnehad on SEC convolicat hybrid aloud solution on American

- Designed, converted, and faunched an SEC compliant hybrid cloud solution on Azure.
- Created ITIL and compliance strategy from scratch, providing high-level security and control over digital assets and formalizing the employee lifecycle.

Riverview Research, LLC – Cleveland, OH., ITIL Consultant 2011-08-15 — 2014-01-25 http://riverviewresearch.com

- Riverview provides comprehensive financial guidance to affluent families and institutional clients.
- Designed and integrated Salesforce into their practice, which previously consisted of Excel spreadsheets.
- Organized and automated their client onboarding process for clients with a net worth over \$50M.
- Organized and automated the collection, processing, and reporting of quarterly performance reports distributed to clients.

### Custom Decal LLC – St. Louis, MO./Grand Junction, CO./Provo, UT., Founder

http://mallstickers.com (accessible on http://web.archive.org)

2008-06-01 — 2012-07-01

- Researched and developed a detailed data analysis algorithm to forecast ideal expansion locations.
- Built a proprietary POS system to manage and track employees and performance on a live server, which included integrated security cams, payroll management, and theft audits.
- Developed eCommerce site with WordPress and built an application in Flash and PHP for customers to design and order their graphics from the website. Linked WooCommerce with proprietary POS system to automate Internet orders.

### **VOLUNTEERING**

### **Project Read, Developer**

2014-03-01 — 2015-03-01

http://projectreadutah.org

- Project Read provides one-on-one tutoring services to adults with low literacy skills and changes lives through literacy by empowering individuals, strengthening families, and building community.
- Converted an outdated, static HTML site into a Wordpress multisite and CMS consisted of four separate sites.
- Although not an ICANN registrar, Kulado Inc. provides at-cost domain registration using a proprietary api algorithm.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Western Governors University**

2015-08-25 — 2016-01-15

Masters of Business Administration - Information Systems Management

**Utah Valley University** 

2011-08-25 — 2014-08-15

Bachelor of Science - Business Management

**SKILLS** 

Innovation (Master): Weird Perspective, Think too much, Unconventional

Management (Really Good): Automation, Productivity, Scalability, Resourceful

INTERESTS Ice Hockey [St. Louis Blues, NHL 18, Dangle, Snipe, Celly], Speed [Engines, Rockets, Formula One], The Universe [String Theory, Relating binary to biology, Losing my mind on those last two topics]